<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Scrolling Text</string>
    <string name="article_title">Disruptive Tech</string>
    <string name="article_subtitle">Buzzing Topic</string>
    <string name="article_text">Disruptive innovation is a kind of innovation that helps in the creation of a new market and value a network and eventually disrupts an existing market and value network, dislodging established market-leading firms, products.
The theory of disruptive innovation has revolutionised the way people think about innovation-driven growth. It garnered the praise of leaders of small, entrepreneurial companies praise it as their guiding star as well as of many executives at large, well-established organisation, including Intel, Southern New Hampshire University.


We\’re currently living in a world where we are spoilt by number of choices and opportunities where new products and services are launched at a rising pace. In the age of innovation, new solutions can be built on top of existing technologies faster than ever before. It implies that there\’s a fresh and large wave of innovation ahead of us and virtually every industry will embrace this change.

In the markets around us many a times we hear about small nascent companies taking over large established companies. This may be due to their new strategies, or tactics or any other factors but it can all be generalised under the umbrella of \‘disruptive innovation\’. The big players basically focuses to sustain the innovations in the market. They try to add different features and options to keep the cream of the market, i.e. higher paying customers. The smaller enterprises provide same basic offerings as the big players but a low cost offering. While the big players over serve the products with contemporary features, smaller enterprise makes the products more appealing to masses by inculcating easy to use features. And thats the dawn of a disruptor disrupting the established market. By the time the big players realise about the disruption the disrupter will be ahead in market.
\n
<b>Disruptive technology</b>
A disruptive technology is one that displaces an orthodox technology and quivers up the industry. Its a pioneering product that creates a completely new industry. In the long run, disruptive technology bypasses, upgrades, or phases out the outmoded technology. They tend to completely alter the we have taken advantage of tech so far.
Some major disruptive technologies examples
Telegraphy to Telephony:
 A communications company called Western Union declined to purchase Alexander Graham Bell\’s telephone patents weighing telegraphy\’s position in the market. But in the long run telephones quickly displaced and disrupted telegraphs.
\n
<b>CRT to LCD/LED</b> :
 CRT were largely dominant during the late 1990s with the improved technologies. But these were very heavy and the size of tube limited maximum screen size to 38 inches. On the other hand LCD/LED were less heavier and offered much larger screen sizes eventually phasing out CRTs.
\n
        <b>Video rental to Video streaming</b> :
 Video rental service used to be a big business, with the mighty rental chain Blockbuster Video having 9,094 stores globally at peak. There came a small company Netflix with the initial idea of mail offerings unlike Blockbuster where a person had to go to a store. But when Netflix expanded to take advantage of the internet for streaming, it became a potential threat to Blockbuster, but was over looked. Netflix even approached Blockbuster in 2000 with the intension of selling out, but it was declined. But Netflix had the last laugh with Blockbuster shutting down 10 years hence due to change in market preferences. Presently there is only one privately owned Blockbuster store in the USA.
\n
<b>Chemical photography to Digital photography</b>:
 Cameras are considered to be one of the most important inventions of mankind. Capturing the frame chemically and developing the negatives was considered to be quiet ordinary process until the advantage digital photography. This had eased several fields with eliminating the need to store and develop films. With powerful batteries and portable hard disks coming handy the Digital photography was given a boost and importantly there wasn\’t a limit to photos or the enthusiasm for it. Eastman Kodak, leader of camera tech of decades, was one of the largest companies to file bankruptcy with the advent of digital cameras.
\n
<b>Some potential opportunities for disruptive innovation</b>:
\n
        <b>Digital Transformation</b>:
 Usage of capricious digital technology to solve problems. Applications like cloud computing is changing the dependence from hardware to software. India has seen a lot of buzz happening in recent times with the push for digitalisation to over come inefficiencies.
\n
        <b>Astroid mining</b>:
 It an emerging fields which aims to exploit the metallic resources present on asteroids and near-earth objects. Its a risky field involving high cost, state of the art tech and rigorous planning. Increasing interest of players in Aerospace is paving a way for viable economic model in the near future.Company called Planetary Resources, financed by Lary Page, founder and former CEO of Google plans to mine and also create fuel deposit in space using water from asteroids.
 \n
Smart city tech:
 It involves application of Internet of Things sensors to collect data from an area and use the data for improving efficiency of services like waste management, water supply management, crime detection, etc. Various governments are pitching for innovative ideas and implementing on a trial basis. The Smart Cities Mission is a retrofitting and urban renewal program being spearheaded by the Ministry of Urban Development, Government of India with the ambition of developing 100 cities by modernising the present mid sized cities.
\n
<b>CRITICISM</b>
Disruptive innovations and tech aren\’t completely flawless. They have their own set of down sides. Disruptive tech do not always succeed and have to battle many risks. Innovators back out in the initial stages fearing survival.
 Companies often see disruptive forces affecting their industry. If an entrenched company sees what\'s going on with disruption, they will generally do anything and everything they can to protect their position in the market - and they\'re often much larger and have more resources than a smaller disruptor. For instance, automobile dealers feel threatened by Tesla\’s direct sale of cars to consumers and so are trying to use regulations and franchise laws to trouble Tesla.
 On the other hand, many business giants have been brought to dust because of the inability to cope up with disruption. Though Kodak developed the digital camera in the 1980s well before anyone else had, but basically sat on it for years because they didn\'t want to ruin the huge profits they were making from selling film. And also many employees loose their jobs because of disruption.
\n
<b>THE FUTURE</b>
AI is predicted to be the next big disruption. Its aim of making human life easier looks promising but fear of losing jobs is very eminent. But nevertheless people should be ready to adapt to whatever radical changes may happen. Disruption is the way we can experiment and evolve for a brighter future.
    \n
    find ou more interesting topics at https://istemanipal.home.blog </string>
</resources>
